A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Medical Interests, Series K FA320
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Hospitals
  - Hospitals - Trudeau Sanatorium, Saranac, New York, 1934-1956 (Box 33, Folder 258)
    John D. Rockefeller, Sr.'s donation to current operating expenses; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s donations to general fund, laboratory cottage, operating expenses, building fund for research and clinical laboratory. Death of Dr. Trudeau. Laurance S. Rockefeller's contribution to Friendowment Fund and operating budgets; contributions by other members of the family. Correspondents include E. L. Trudeau, William H. Welch, Dr. Laurason Broun, Federick Sheffield, Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, Willard S. Richardson, Laurance S. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Sr., John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Trudeau Sanatorium, Saranac, New York, 1934-1956 (Box 33, Folder 0258A)
  - Hospitals - Tucson Medical Center, 1949-1961 (Box 33, Folder 259)
    Mr. and Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions. Memorial gift and plaque. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - United Hospital Fund, 1897-1925 (Box 33, Folder 260)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contributions, Laura Spelman Rockefeller Memorial contributions; plans for survey of hospital situation in New York; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s declination of invitation to serve as member of Campaign Committee; plans for annual campaign drives. Printed materials, auditors reports, progress of fund-raising campaigns, financial and statistical data; summary of Rockefeller Brothers Fund contributions. Correspondents include W. H. P. Faunce, Frederick Greene, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller, Sr., Arthur Woods, Arthur W. Packard, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - United Hospital Fund, 1926-1942 (Box 33, Folder 261)
  - Hospitals - United Hospital Fund, 1945-1961 (Box 33, Folder 262)
  - Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1934-1947 (Box 34, Folder 263)
  - Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Abby Rockefeller Mauzé, 1939-1961 (Box 34, Folder 264)
  - Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Laurance S. Rockefeller, 1936-1961 (Box 34, Folder 265)
    Request for contributions, declined. Mary French Rockefeller contributions. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Contributions, 1928-1936 (Box 34, Folder 266)
  - Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Contributions, 1940-1961 (Box 34, Folder 267)
  - Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Hospital Building and Modernization, 1957-1959 (Box 34, Folder 268)
  - Hospitals - United Hospital Fund - Clippings, 1944-1959 (Box 34, Folder 269)
  - Hospitals - White Plains Hospital, 1937-1959 (Box 35, Folder 270)
    Request for contribution to hospital for White Plains; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. declines because of his responsibility to Tarrytown hospital. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur W. Packard.
  - Hospitals - Dr. Wilmer Foundation Hospital, Washington, DC, 1923-1939 (Box 35, Folder 271)
    List of contributions and trustees of William Holland Wilmer Foundation; plans for model hospital to study diseases of the eye. Certificate of incorporation and by-laws; contribution from General Education Board; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s attempts to interest Henry Ford in making contribution. Correspondents include Henry Breckinridge, A. Flexner, Thomas B. Appleget, William H. Welch, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Hospitals - Women's and Children's Dispensary, Cleveland, Ohio, 1899-1919 (Box 35, Folder 272)
- Social Medicine
  - Social Medicine, 1930-1961 (Box 35, Folder 273)
    Suggested plans for financing medical care. No family interest expressed. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John Dr. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard.
    210
- Health Insurance Plan
  - Health Insurance Plan, 1944-1958 (Box 35, Folder 274)
    210.1